<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>First Time in Toronto Airport</title>
    <link>https://sabjin.com/t/first-time-in-toronto-airport/110</link>
    <description>**What You Should Know When Entering Canada Through Toronto Airport.**

Entering the Toronto airport on your first visit to Canada, there are different things you should be mindful of that would make your travel experience much easier than you would expect. In this post, you should find all the T&#39;s and I&#39;s needed for a seamless travel experience into Canada when coming through the Toronto airport. 

**What To Expect.** 
1. Expect a busy sight. 
One of the notable things about Canada&#39;s Toronto Airport is that it is usually busy. Statistically, with just two terminals, the airport reportedly takes off and lands more than 1,000 flights per day. This averages to almost or over 50 million passengers in a year. For a first-time traveller, especially if you are coming from a country with airports not as crowdy as this, expect to see a crowd. 
2. Knowing your terminals. 
To avoid getting lost through the airport space, it is required that you have an idea of what terminal you are in and how to make your way out. There used to be three terminals until 2007, when Terminal 3 was destroyed during renovation. This makes Terminal 3 terminal 2. Emirates, Air Canada, and all other Star Alliance airlines have check-in counters in Terminal 1, while All SkyTeam (Delta) and OneWorld (American and British Airways) member airlines use Terminal 2 (3).
But, should in case you get confused at any point, you are free to make your way to the security to ask for more explicit directions. 
3. Transport Out of the terminal. 
The Union Pearson Express (or UP Express) is an airport rail link that runs every 15 minutes between Union Station and Toronto Pearson International Airport. The trip takes only 25 minutes and costs 12.35 CAD for a one-way trip and $24.70 for a round trip. If rail transport seems like a hassle, four buses transport passengers from the airport to downtown and the suburbs. 
The TTC bus connects to the subway system; GO Transit provides routes to the suburbs; MiWay operates only locally throughout Mississauga, and Brampton Transit serves the city of Brampton. 
4. Rest and refreshment. 
From quick coffee shops and familiar fast-food chains to world-class cuisine served to your table, passengers are given the utmost luxury possible when in-between transit or waiting for guides through the city. 
And if you are traveling heavy yet need refreshment before heading out of the airport, it would interest you to know that passengers are allowed to store luggage anywhere in either terminal from $6 to $12.50. However, this strictly depends on the luggage size and storage duration.

**Check Point and Clearance.**
When you arrive at the terminal, proceed to the first CBSA checkpoint, Primary Inspection. At this point, a border services officer will examine your Declaration Card, identification, and other travel documents.
When you are directed to a booth, you may be asked questions to determine your immigration status, the nature of any goods you bring with you, your duty-free allowance, and your exemption entitlements. 

**What You Shouldn’t Do.** 
You want to be sure to declare all your luggage at the checkpoint while taking into consideration properties that are not eligible since they would be confiscated at the point. 
Lastly, if you need to reach out to someone and your travel leaves you with a dead phone, be assured that different outlets for charging mobile devices can be found at all the gates. Plus, there is free WIFI, thanks to American Express.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 03:26:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Uncategorized</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sabjin.com/t/first-time-in-toronto-airport/110.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>First Time in Toronto Airport</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Delaram Soofi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strong>What You Should Know When Entering Canada Through Toronto Airport.</strong></p>
<p>Entering the Toronto airport on your first visit to Canada, there are different things you should be mindful of that would make your travel experience much easier than you would expect. In this post, you should find all the T’s and I’s needed for a seamless travel experience into Canada when coming through the Toronto airport.</p>
<p><strong>What To Expect.</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Expect a busy sight.<br>
One of the notable things about Canada’s Toronto Airport is that it is usually busy. Statistically, with just two terminals, the airport reportedly takes off and lands more than 1,000 flights per day. This averages to almost or over 50 million passengers in a year. For a first-time traveller, especially if you are coming from a country with airports not as crowdy as this, expect to see a crowd.</li>
<li>Knowing your terminals.<br>
To avoid getting lost through the airport space, it is required that you have an idea of what terminal you are in and how to make your way out. There used to be three terminals until 2007, when Terminal 3 was destroyed during renovation. This makes Terminal 3 terminal 2. Emirates, Air Canada, and all other Star Alliance airlines have check-in counters in Terminal 1, while All SkyTeam (Delta) and OneWorld (American and British Airways) member airlines use Terminal 2 (3).<br>
But, should in case you get confused at any point, you are free to make your way to the security to ask for more explicit directions.</li>
<li>Transport Out of the terminal.<br>
The Union Pearson Express (or UP Express) is an airport rail link that runs every 15 minutes between Union Station and Toronto Pearson International Airport. The trip takes only 25 minutes and costs 12.35 CAD for a one-way trip and $24.70 for a round trip. If rail transport seems like a hassle, four buses transport passengers from the airport to downtown and the suburbs.<br>
The TTC bus connects to the subway system; GO Transit provides routes to the suburbs; MiWay operates only locally throughout Mississauga, and Brampton Transit serves the city of Brampton.</li>
<li>Rest and refreshment.<br>
From quick coffee shops and familiar fast-food chains to world-class cuisine served to your table, passengers are given the utmost luxury possible when in-between transit or waiting for guides through the city.<br>
And if you are traveling heavy yet need refreshment before heading out of the airport, it would interest you to know that passengers are allowed to store luggage anywhere in either terminal from $6 to $12.50. However, this strictly depends on the luggage size and storage duration.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Check Point and Clearance.</strong><br>
When you arrive at the terminal, proceed to the first CBSA checkpoint, Primary Inspection. At this point, a border services officer will examine your Declaration Card, identification, and other travel documents.<br>
When you are directed to a booth, you may be asked questions to determine your immigration status, the nature of any goods you bring with you, your duty-free allowance, and your exemption entitlements.</p>
<p><strong>What You Shouldn’t Do.</strong><br>
You want to be sure to declare all your luggage at the checkpoint while taking into consideration properties that are not eligible since they would be confiscated at the point.<br>
Lastly, if you need to reach out to someone and your travel leaves you with a dead phone, be assured that different outlets for charging mobile devices can be found at all the gates. Plus, there is free WIFI, thanks to American Express.</p>
          <p><a href="https://sabjin.com/t/first-time-in-toronto-airport/110/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/first-time-in-toronto-airport/110/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 03:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-110-1</guid>
        <source url="https://sabjin.com/t/first-time-in-toronto-airport/110.rss">First Time in Toronto Airport</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
