<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sabjin - Latest posts</title>
    <link>https://sabjin.com</link>
    <description>Latest posts</description> 
      <item>
        <title>How to Find Halal Food in Cleveland</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mohammad Mohammad Virayesh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Finding Halal food in Cleveland, OH can be a challenge, especially if you are new to the area. Halal food is prepared in accordance with Islamic law, and it is important for many Muslims to be able to access this type of food. Fortunately, there are a few ways to find Halal food in Cleveland, and this article will provide you with some helpful tips.</p>
<p>One of the best ways to find Halal food in Cleveland is to use online resources. There are several websites and apps that can help you locate Halal restaurants and grocery stores in the area. For example, Zabihah is a popular website that allows you to search for Halal restaurants by location. You can also use the Halal Food Guide app, which provides detailed information about Halal restaurants and grocery stores in Cleveland and other cities around the world.</p>
<p>Another way to find Halal food in Cleveland is to ask your Muslim friends or colleagues for recommendations. Many people in the Muslim community are familiar with Halal food options in the area, and they may be able to point you in the right direction. You can also visit a local mosque and speak with the imam or other members of the community. They may be able to provide you with information about Halal food options in Cleveland.</p>
<p>In addition to these online and community-based resources, you can also try visiting ethnic grocery stores or markets in Cleveland. Many of these stores carry a wide variety of Halal food options, including meat, dairy products, and other items. You can also look for Halal labels on food products at regular grocery stores. These labels will indicate that the food has been prepared in accordance with Islamic law.</p>
<p>Overall, finding Halal food in Cleveland can take some effort, but it is definitely possible. By using the resources and tips outlined in this article, you should be able to locate a variety of Halal food options in the Cleveland area. This will allow you to enjoy delicious and authentic Halal food, and to maintain your dietary requirements while living in Cleveland.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/how-to-find-halal-food-in-cleveland/122#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 15:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-254</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>سفر به ایران</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@pardis90 Pardis Timsar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>سلام دوستان،<br>
میخواستم ببینم اخیرا کسی ایران رفته؟ فرودگاه چطور رفتار میکنن و آیا قوانین جدیدی برای بررسی تلفن های همراه وضع شده؟</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/121#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 02:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-253</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>انتقال پول در ایران</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@POmidvar P Omidvar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <aside class="quote no-group" data-username="navidad" data-post="5" data-topic="59">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img loading="lazy" alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://sjc6.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/user_avatar/sabjin.com/navidad/40/72_2.png" class="avatar"> Navid Tousi:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>ایرونی</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>میتونید یک وی پی ان ایران با هزینه کم خریداری کنید  و از نرم افزار بانکهایی که برای رمز دوم احتیاجی به دریافت پیامک نداشته باشند (مثل سامان و تجارت) استفاده کرد.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/59#post_6</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 04:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-252</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>کله پاچه نزدیکی های دنور</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@POmidvar P Omidvar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>ظاهرا کله پزی قبلا بوده ولی بسته شده. کله پاچه خام رو میشه از فروشگاههای آرش و زم زم و المصطفی خریداری کرد</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/46#post_2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 04:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-251</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>نون ایرونی در Denver</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@POmidvar P Omidvar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>زم زم هم نون های بربری خوبی داره</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/denver/44#post_4</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 04:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-250</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Flying to USA from Canada</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@pardis90 Pardis Timsar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Yeah Farhad, what’s your citizenship and residency status?</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/flying-to-usa-from-canada/96#post_3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 20:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-247</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>خرید لپ‌تاپ خوب</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@pardis90 Pardis Timsar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Costco</p>
<p>Best Buy</p>
<p>Amazon</p>
<p>Apple Store</p>
<p><img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=12" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji only-emoji" alt=":slight_smile:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/108#post_2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 20:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-246</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>بازی های جام جهانی</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@pardis90 Pardis Timsar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>وبسایت های Telewebion و Tamashaland همیشه شبکه های ایران رو به صورت زنده آنلاین نشون میدن. به نظرم موقع جام جهانی باید بازی ها رو شبکه 3 با گزارش فارسی نشون بده.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/116#post_3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 20:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-245</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>بازی های جام جهانی</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@farshid Farshid Tayebi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>آقا فرهاد <a href="https://sabjin.com/t/topic/101">اینجا</a> یه توضیح خیلی خوب و دقیق از روش های مختلف دیدن شبکه های ایرانی و صدا و سیما در آمریکا دادن:<br>
<a href="https://sabjin.com/t/topic/101" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://sabjin.com/t/topic/101</a></p>
<p>حالا به طور خاص برای جام جهانی، آپشن های خیلی بهتری هم هست که من اینجا توضیح میدم.</p>
<p>شبکه فاکس اسپورت: شبکه تلویزیونی Fox Sports و FS1 بازی های رو بصورت مستقیم با گزارش انگلیسی پخش میکنه. اگه توی پلن Cable TVتون این شبکه رو ندارین میتونین با شرکت Cable TVتون تماس بگیرین تا شبکه رو برای ماه جام جهانی به لیست شبکه هاتون اضافه کنید.<br>
<a href="https://www.foxsports.com/soccer/2022-fifa-world-cup/scores" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://www.foxsports.com/soccer/2022-fifa-world-cup/scores</a></p>
<p>اپ FuboTV: اگه Cable TV ندارین میتونین از طریق stream کردن بازی های رو ببینین. یکی از اپ هایی که شبکه Fox Sports رو داره اپ Fubo TV هست که با 69 دلار در ماه (که فقط میتونین برای ماه جام جهانی تهیه کنید) سابسکریپشن Pro رو تهیه کنید و بازی ها رو از طریق اینترنت یا اپ Smart TV نگاه کنید.<br>
<a href="https://www.fubo.tv/welcome" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://www.fubo.tv/welcome</a></p>
<p>غیر از Fubo TV، سرویس Sling TV هم هست که یکم ارزون تره (40 دلار) و کانال های کمتری رو داره ولی کانالهایی که بازی های جام جهانی رو نشون میدن رو داره. اونم خوبه:<br>
<a href="https://www.sling.com/pm/homepage" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://www.sling.com/pm/homepage</a></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/116#post_2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 21:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-242</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>بازی های جام جهانی</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@navidad Navid Tousi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>بازی های جام جهانی رو توی آمریکا از کجا میشه بصورت پخش زنده نگاه کرد؟</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/116#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 05:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-241</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The Difference Between Kosher and Halal Foods</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@farhad Farhad Tasnimpour]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>With so many dietary restrictions and food allergies these days, it’s important to know the difference between various types of foods. Two terms that you may have heard of are “kosher” and “halal.” But what do they mean? Essentially, kosher and halal refer to two different ways of preparing food. Here’s a closer look at the difference between kosher and halal foods.</p>
<p><strong>Kosher Foods</strong></p>
<p>Kosher foods are those that comply with the strict dietary standards of Jewish law. For a food to be considered kosher, it must be prepared in a certain way and free of certain substances. For example, kosher laws forbid the consumption of pork products or shellfish. In addition, meat and dairy products cannot be mixed together. Beyond that, there are other restrictions on how kosher foods can be prepared. For example, blood must be drained from meat before it can be eaten.</p>
<p><strong>Halal Foods</strong></p>
<p>Halal foods are those that comply with Islamic law. The word “halal” means “permissible.” So, in order for a food to be considered halal, it must not contain any forbidden ingredients and it must be prepared in a certain way. For example, halal laws forbid the consumption of pork products, alcohol, or animals that have been killed in a cruel way. In addition, meat and dairy products cannot be mixed together. Halal laws also require that blood be drained from meat before it is consumed.</p>
<p><strong>How to know if a product is Kosher or Halal</strong></p>
<p>There are a few ways to tell if a product is Kosher or Halal. One way is to look for Kosher or Halal symbols on the product. Kosher symbols include the letter “K” or “U” inside a circle, while Halal symbols include the words “Halal” or “Muslim.” Another way to tell if a product is Kosher or Halal is to check the ingredient list. Kosher and Halal foods will have different ingredients than non-Kosher and non-Halal foods. Finally, you can always contact the manufacturer of the product to ask if it is Kosher or Halal.</p>
<p><strong>Food That Can Be Both Kosher and Halal</strong></p>
<p>Kosher food that is prepared by Jewish dietary law would be considered halal if it followed Islamic dietary law as well. Similarly, the halal food will also be kosher food that is prepared according to both Islamic and Jewish dietary laws. This is because the two diets have many similarities, and both prohibit the consumption of certain animals and animal products. Such as both Islamic and Jewish dietary law require that blood be drained from meat before it is consumed and forbid the consumption of pork products.</p>
<p>Both kosher and halal foods follow similar preparation techniques and have similar forbidden ingredients. The main difference between these two types of foods is that Kosher food is prepared according to Jewish law while Halal food is prepared according to Islamic law. When in doubt about what type of food to buy or eat, always check with the manufacturer or restaurant to see if the food is kosher or halal.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/the-difference-between-kosher-and-halal-foods/114#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 17:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-238</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>نون ایرونی در Denver</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@POmidvar P Omidvar]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>You may try<br>
Shahrzad Bakery<br>
House of Bread<br>
Al Mostafa<br>
Sara Bread<br>
All in city of Aurora</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/denver/44#post_3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 01:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-237</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Social Security Card and SSN in USA</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@marzii Marzieh Akbarpour]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p><strong>All You Need to Know About the Social Security Number and Social Security Card in The United States.</strong></p>
<p>For a new immigrant, it is not unlikely that you must have heard the term Social Security Number or SSN, as it is mainly called. Are you wondering what it is and if you should get one? In this post, we go over the basics of an SSN and every other thing you need to know about an SSN as an immigrant.</p>
<p>What is a Social Security Number?</p>
<ul>
<li>A Social Security number (SSN) is a numerical identifier assigned to U.S. citizens and other residents. The origin of the social security number dates back to 1936. The integration into the security system was basically to provide retirement and disability benefits for U.S. citizens. But as you would see in the rest of this post, it has grown to be more than that.</li>
</ul>
<p>What does a Social Security Number Entail?</p>
<ul>
<li>You must understand that while a social security number might contain a series of random numbers, the numbers are far from random. There is a set metric for how they are given. Each SSN is a compilation of three groups of numbers. This is the area number, group number, and serial number.<br>
The first three numbers on an SSN are the area number, and every area has a definitive structure of numbers assigned to the area. At the same time, the group number refers to the SSN issuing office, which ranges from 01-99. The serial number, on the other hand, is made in such a way that it ascends from 0001 to 9999 within each group. 0000 is never given, and no two persons have the same four serial number digits.</li>
</ul>
<p>Why do I need a Social Security Number?</p>
<ul>
<li>Coming into the United States, you want to make sure that you get every benefit that applies to you. More so, during applications for job offers, passport applications, loans request, tax payments, and driver’s license applications, it is required that you input your social security number. This number makes it possible to track and apply for benefits.<br>
Getting an SSN and the SSN card showing the number as an immigrant requires you to fill out Form SS-5: Application for a Social Security Card from the SSA. While going through the form, you would see how to obtain an original card, replace a card, and change or correct SSN records. However, obtaining these cards and numbers comes with a couple of requirements, such as documentation that proves age, identity, and immigration status. All at zero cost.</li>
</ul>
<p>What should you do if your Social Security Number Card is Stolen?</p>
<ul>
<li>It is pretty common these days to hear of identity thieves. But once you suspect that your identity has been stolen and your social security number has been used by someone else, you are required to act immediately.<br>
Contact the Social Security Administration if you suspect income-related problems after reporting the suspected criminal activity to your financial institutions and credit reporting agencies. You can also file complaints with <a href="http://IdentityTheft.gov" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">IdentityTheft.gov</a>, the Internal Revenue Service, and the Internet Crime Center to report any suspicious activity.</li>
</ul> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/social-security-card-and-ssn-in-usa/112#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 21:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-235</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>First Time in Toronto Airport</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@deli Delaram Soofi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p><strong>What You Should Know When Entering Canada Through Toronto Airport.</strong></p>
<p>Entering the Toronto airport on your first visit to Canada, there are different things you should be mindful of that would make your travel experience much easier than you would expect. In this post, you should find all the T’s and I’s needed for a seamless travel experience into Canada when coming through the Toronto airport.</p>
<p><strong>What To Expect.</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Expect a busy sight.<br>
One of the notable things about Canada’s Toronto Airport is that it is usually busy. Statistically, with just two terminals, the airport reportedly takes off and lands more than 1,000 flights per day. This averages to almost or over 50 million passengers in a year. For a first-time traveller, especially if you are coming from a country with airports not as crowdy as this, expect to see a crowd.</li>
<li>Knowing your terminals.<br>
To avoid getting lost through the airport space, it is required that you have an idea of what terminal you are in and how to make your way out. There used to be three terminals until 2007, when Terminal 3 was destroyed during renovation. This makes Terminal 3 terminal 2. Emirates, Air Canada, and all other Star Alliance airlines have check-in counters in Terminal 1, while All SkyTeam (Delta) and OneWorld (American and British Airways) member airlines use Terminal 2 (3).<br>
But, should in case you get confused at any point, you are free to make your way to the security to ask for more explicit directions.</li>
<li>Transport Out of the terminal.<br>
The Union Pearson Express (or UP Express) is an airport rail link that runs every 15 minutes between Union Station and Toronto Pearson International Airport. The trip takes only 25 minutes and costs 12.35 CAD for a one-way trip and $24.70 for a round trip. If rail transport seems like a hassle, four buses transport passengers from the airport to downtown and the suburbs.<br>
The TTC bus connects to the subway system; GO Transit provides routes to the suburbs; MiWay operates only locally throughout Mississauga, and Brampton Transit serves the city of Brampton.</li>
<li>Rest and refreshment.<br>
From quick coffee shops and familiar fast-food chains to world-class cuisine served to your table, passengers are given the utmost luxury possible when in-between transit or waiting for guides through the city.<br>
And if you are traveling heavy yet need refreshment before heading out of the airport, it would interest you to know that passengers are allowed to store luggage anywhere in either terminal from $6 to $12.50. However, this strictly depends on the luggage size and storage duration.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Check Point and Clearance.</strong><br>
When you arrive at the terminal, proceed to the first CBSA checkpoint, Primary Inspection. At this point, a border services officer will examine your Declaration Card, identification, and other travel documents.<br>
When you are directed to a booth, you may be asked questions to determine your immigration status, the nature of any goods you bring with you, your duty-free allowance, and your exemption entitlements.</p>
<p><strong>What You Shouldn’t Do.</strong><br>
You want to be sure to declare all your luggage at the checkpoint while taking into consideration properties that are not eligible since they would be confiscated at the point.<br>
Lastly, if you need to reach out to someone and your travel leaves you with a dead phone, be assured that different outlets for charging mobile devices can be found at all the gates. Plus, there is free WIFI, thanks to American Express.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/first-time-in-toronto-airport/110#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 03:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-233</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>انتقال پول بین دوستان در آمریکا</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@benjamin Ben Hakimi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>آقا گوگل و اپل و فیسبوک هم اپ دارن برای این کار ولی تقریبا هیچ کس ازشون استفاده نمیکنه <img src="https://emoji.discourse-cdn.com/twitter/rofl.png?v=12" title=":rofl:" class="emoji" alt=":rofl:" loading="lazy" width="20" height="20"></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/107#post_2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 22:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-231</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>خرید لپ‌تاپ خوب</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@benjamin Ben Hakimi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>سلام به همه دوستای خوبم… لپ‌ تاپ خوب از کجا میشه خرید؟ من آمریکا زندگی میکنم و دنبال یه لپ‌تاپ خوب میگردم که باهاش کدنویسی و پایتون رو یاد بگیرم.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/108#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 22:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-230</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>ورود به آمریکا</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@benjamin Ben Hakimi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I have brought in pistachios with no problems all the time!</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/93#post_3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 18:08:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-229</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>خرید ماشین از کاروانا</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@farshid Farshid Tayebi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>خود شرکت کاروانا که صد در صد معتبره و مشکلی نداره ولی ماشینی که میخواین بخرید رو حتما Carfax Report اون رو چک کنید. گاهی اوقات خود Carvana ریپورت رو بهتون نشون میده ولی با شماره VIN خودتون میتونین Carfax Report رو بخرید و بررسی کنید.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/105#post_3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 22:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-228</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>خرید ماشین از کاروانا</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@usa_fa Farhad Allayari]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>یکی از دوستان من از این طریق یک ماشین تهیه کرد که ماشین رو مستقیم دم خونه بهش تحویل دادن. بعد از یه مدت از ماشین به دلایل ظاهری راضی نبود و return کرد. مجددا برگشتند و ماشین رو از دم خونه برداشتن. کلا از پروسه خیلی راضی بود.</p>
<p>شرکت معتبریه، فکر نمیکنم مشکلی به وجود بیاد.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/105#post_2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 22:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-227</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>انتقال پول بین دوستان در آمریکا</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@usa_fa Farhad Allayari]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>زمان‌‌هایی پیش میاد که دوست شما برای شما خریدی انجام میده، یا یک نفر صورت‌حساب رستوران رو برای یک گروه حساب میکنه، یا همخونه شما پول کرایه خونه رو پرداخت میکنه و … . چطور میتونین این مقدار پول رو به طرف پرداخت کنید؟</p>
<p>راه اول: اپ ونمو Venmo<br>
</p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/original/1X/cf2d2e86dbce43445dbf616dd964c3af941165b6.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/tyLDxNJU0M7EhnvBrgfskEhr2D4.png?dl=1" title="Venmo-Logo1" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/cf2d2e86dbce43445dbf616dd964c3af941165b6_2_207x116.png" alt="Venmo-Logo1" data-base62-sha1="tyLDxNJU0M7EhnvBrgfskEhr2D4" width="207" height="116" srcset="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/cf2d2e86dbce43445dbf616dd964c3af941165b6_2_207x116.png, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/cf2d2e86dbce43445dbf616dd964c3af941165b6_2_310x174.png 1.5x, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/cf2d2e86dbce43445dbf616dd964c3af941165b6_2_414x232.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/cf2d2e86dbce43445dbf616dd964c3af941165b6_2_10x10.png"></a></div><p></p>
<p>که هم برای آیفون و هم اندروید وجود داره و بین آمریکایی ها خیلی رواج داره. این اپ متعلق به شرکت PayPal هست و تفاوتش در اینه که بیشتر برای تراکنش های مالی بین دوست و خانواده انجام میشه در حالی که PayPal برای تراکنش های تجاری و خرید و فروش استفاده میشه.<br>
<a href="https://venmo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://venmo.com/</a></p>
<p>اینطوریه که وقتی اپ رو نصب میکنید و اکانت میسازید، به شما یک حساب جداگونه از حساب بانکی شما میده. اون وقتی میتونین حساب بانکی خودتون رو به اکانت Venmo وصل کنید و راحت بین Venmo و حساب بانکیتون پول انتقال بدین. برای انتقال پول به بقیه هم فقط کافیه که ID اونها توی Venmo رو بدونین و توی اپ راحت میتونین براشون پول انتقال بدین.</p>
<p>راه معمول دوم: Zelle<br>
</p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/original/1X/4a441cab2f654c1f8bc0f6ea9fa1d750aa783602.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/aAZgfpdHj41OCRsOhfYNa0TWM6K.png?dl=1" title="Zelle-logo1" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/4a441cab2f654c1f8bc0f6ea9fa1d750aa783602_2_172x97.png" alt="Zelle-logo1" data-base62-sha1="aAZgfpdHj41OCRsOhfYNa0TWM6K" width="172" height="97" srcset="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/4a441cab2f654c1f8bc0f6ea9fa1d750aa783602_2_172x97.png, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/4a441cab2f654c1f8bc0f6ea9fa1d750aa783602_2_258x145.png 1.5x, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/4a441cab2f654c1f8bc0f6ea9fa1d750aa783602_2_344x194.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/4a441cab2f654c1f8bc0f6ea9fa1d750aa783602_2_10x10.png"></a></div><br>
در آمریکا سیستم یک پارچه بانکی بین بانک ها (مشابه شبکه شتاب در ایران) وجود نداره. برای انتقال پول بین حساب های بانکی باید از Wire یا نوشتن چک استفاده کرد که همشون هزینه (fee) اضافه دارن و برای انتقال وجه های کوچیک خیلی به صرفه نیستند. حالا شرکت خصوصی Zelle اومده و این شبکه بین بانکی رو یه جورایی ایجاد کرده. کار این شرکت اینه که با اکثر بانک های بزرگ در ارتباطه و خودش رو به عنوان یک سرویس اضافه در سیستم‌های بانکی قرار داده. شما می‌تونین از طریق شماره تلفن یا آدرس ایمیلتون، قابلیت Zelle رو در حساب بانکیتون فعال کنید و اونوقت از طریق Zelle برای سایرین پول بفرستید یا دریافت کنید.<p></p>
<p>راه معمول سوم: CashApp<br>
</p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/original/1X/80af794401c9a15885fcbec3a6d80b68ccd8ca2e.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/imp493GAh0iTnFPqGDosuY2X5MO.png?dl=1" title="CashApp-10241" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/80af794401c9a15885fcbec3a6d80b68ccd8ca2e_2_125x125.png" alt="CashApp-10241" data-base62-sha1="imp493GAh0iTnFPqGDosuY2X5MO" width="125" height="125" srcset="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/80af794401c9a15885fcbec3a6d80b68ccd8ca2e_2_125x125.png, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/80af794401c9a15885fcbec3a6d80b68ccd8ca2e_2_187x187.png 1.5x, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/80af794401c9a15885fcbec3a6d80b68ccd8ca2e_2_250x250.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/80af794401c9a15885fcbec3a6d80b68ccd8ca2e_2_10x10.png"></a></div><p></p>
<p>یه اپ دیگه که خیلی مشابه به Venmo هست ولی به اندازه Venmo حداقل هنوز همه گیر نشده.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>نکته مهم:</strong><br>
تمام تراکنش‌های مالی بیشتر از 625 دلار به اداره مالیات آمریکا گزارش میشن. گزارش شدنشون به اداره مالیات اتفاق بدی نیست و به این معنی نیست که شما باید روی تمام انتقال‌های بیشتر از 625 دلار مالیات بدین. فقط به این معنی هست که در صورت لزوم اداره مالیات (IRS) این اجازه رو داره که از شما بپرسه علت این انتقال پول چه بوده. اگر این انتقال پول بابت کسب درآمد برای شما بوده، اونوقت باید به عنوان درآمد سالانه حساب بشه و مالیاتش پرداخت بشه. ولی اگر این انقال پول بین دوستان و صرفا برای صاف کردن بدهی های کوچیک و … بوده باشه که اصلا هیچ اهمیتی نداره. علت اینکه اکثر این اپ ها و سرویس ها از شما شماره SSN رو می پرسند هم دقیقا همینه تا تراکنش های بیشتر از 625 دلار رو بتونن گزارش بدن</p>
<hr>
<p>شما از چه سرویس هایی برای انتقال پول با وجه کم بین دوستاتون استفاده میکنید یا میشناسید؟</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/107#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 22:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-226</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>خرید ماشین از کاروانا</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@nasringoldasht Nasrin Goldasht]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>کسی تا حالا از کاروانا ماشین خریده؟ معتبره و میشه به ماشین هاش اعتماد کرد و این که آیا واقعا ماشین رو میارن دم در خونه؟</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/105#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-224</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Global Entry &amp; TSA Pre دریافت</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@usa_fa Farhad Allayari]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>اداره امنیت حمل و نقل آمریکا (TSA) یه بخشی از وزارت امنیت داخلی آمریکاست (Department of Homeland Security) که وظیفه امنیت فرودگاه ها و پروازها رو به عهده داره. اون قسمت از فرودگاه که بازرسی بدنی و وسایل انجام میشه توسط TSA مدیریت میشه و معمولاً در روزهای تعطیل صف های طولانی داره و باعث دردسر خیلی از مسافرهاست. اما افرادی که ملیت آمریکایی یا اقامت دائم دارند (دارندگان Green Card) میتونن که برای دریافت TSA Pre اقدام کنند و بعد از بررسی سابقه، پرداخت هزینه و گذراندن یک مصاحبه، یک شماره تحت عنوان Known Traveler Number دریافت میکنند. این شماره رو میشه زمان خرید بلیط پرواز وارد کرد تا کارت پرواز شما دارای لوگوی TSA Pre بشه.</p>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/original/1X/ae48d595277923d168a056ed2fd150940a58b530.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/oRN7QOe6joO40WiZIEXVdwx28uc.png?dl=1" title="TSA_Precheck_logo.svg" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/ae48d595277923d168a056ed2fd150940a58b530_2_345x119.png" alt="TSA_Precheck_logo.svg" data-base62-sha1="oRN7QOe6joO40WiZIEXVdwx28uc" width="345" height="119" srcset="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/ae48d595277923d168a056ed2fd150940a58b530_2_345x119.png, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/ae48d595277923d168a056ed2fd150940a58b530_2_517x178.png 1.5x, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/ae48d595277923d168a056ed2fd150940a58b530_2_690x238.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/ae48d595277923d168a056ed2fd150940a58b530_2_10x10.png"></a></div><p></p>
<p>دارندگان TSA Pre این اجازه رو دارن که از صف های جداگانه ای که معمولاً طول کمتری دارند حرکت کنند و چون سابقه اونها بررسی شده بازرسی بدنی آنها هم سریع تر انجام میشه. مثلا در بیشتر اوقات نیازی به درآوردن کفش نیست و معمولاً نیازی نیست که لپ تاپ از کیف در بیاد و … .</p>
<p>در کنار TSA Pre، برنامه جامع تری به اسم Global Entry هم وجود داره. کارت گلوبال انتری علاوه بر تمام مزایای TSA Pre، به شما این قابلیت رو خارج از مرزهای آمریکا در بیشتر کشورهای اروپایی و کانادا هم میده.</p>
<p><img src="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/original/1X/95eac0ba4b7f75e46ff77bbfcd0af63484aca31b.jpeg" alt="Global_entry_card" data-base62-sha1="loe67z8xaPQ8SG2AxQnjBz8MutZ" width="313" height="203"></p>
<p>زمانی که بعد از یک پرواز بین المللی وارد مرزهای آمریکا میشید صف جداگانه ای برای دارندگان این کارت وجود داره که میتونن از طریق دستگاه های خوددار و با عکس چهره شناسایی بشن و مدارکشون سریع تر بررسی بشه.</p>
<p><img src="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/original/1X/622546811636d0e9cfcab0feb3d96e5434a63b1f.png" alt="Screenshot 2022-09-08 124130" data-base62-sha1="e0eEz6Y432m2ZXHYfsnbJrjrepx" width="517" height="387"></p>
<p>برای دریافت TSA Pre یا Global Entry میتونین از طریق وبسایت زیر اقدام کنید:<br>
<a href="https://ttp.dhs.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://ttp.dhs.gov/</a></p>
<p>چند نکته:</p>
<ol>
<li>کانادا برنامه مشابهی داره تحت عنوان Nexus که این دو برنامه همدیگه رو قبول دارند. به این معنی که دارندگان Nexus میتونن از صف های Global Entry استفاده کنند و بر عکس.</li>
<li>کردیت کارت های مسافرتی معمولاً هزینه application های کارت های Global Entry و TSA Pre رو پرداخت می کنند.</li>
<li>برای عبور سریعتر بین آمریکا و دو کشور همسایه (کانادا و مکزیک) برنامه دیگری وجود داره به اسم Sentri که برای افرادی که ملیت آمریکایی یا اقامت دائم ندارند هم قابل دریافت هست.</li>
</ol> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/global-entry-tsa-pre/104#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 17:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-223</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>تغییر آدرس در آمریکا</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@saba Saba Jamalian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>اگر که شهروند آمریکا نیستید و روی یک نوع ویزای مهاجرتی یا دانشجویی هستید، همیشه باید هر گونه تعییر آدرستون رو به اداره مهاجرت (USCIS) گزارش بدین. برای این کار باید فرم AR-11 رو پر کنید که هم میشه پست کرد و هم خوشبختانه میشه بصورت آنلاین اون رو فرستاد:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.uscis.gov/addresschange" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.uscis.gov/addresschange</a></p>
<p>بهتره که تغییر آدرستون رو به شرکت های پستی هم اطلاع بدین. خوبی این کار اینه اگه نامه یا بسته ای به آدرس قدیمی شما ارسال بشه، شرکت پستی میتونه اون رو به آدرس جدیدتون بفرسته.</p>
<p>تغییر آدرس با اداره پست ملی آمریکا:<br>
<a href="https://usps.com/move" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://usps.com/move</a></p>
<p>و با پست خصوصی UPS:<br>
<a href="https://www.ups.com/us/en/support/tracking-support/change-delivery-options.page" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.ups.com/us/en/support/tracking-support/change-delivery-options.page</a></p>
<p>یه جای دیگه که اهمیت داره، آدرستون با محل کارتون هست. اگه جایی کار میکنید و یا تحصیل میکنید آدرستون رو به روز کنید.</p>
<p>و اینکه حواستون باشه که آدرستون رو با بانکتون و کارت های اعتباریتون به روز کنید تا نامه ها و statement هاتون به جای درست ارسال بشه.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/102#post_2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 19:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-221</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>تغییر آدرس در آمریکا</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@sgiarsoorati Mohammadreza Fathi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>بعد از هر گونه تغییر آدرس در آمریکا چه کارهایی واجب هست که باید حتما انجام بشه؟</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/102#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 19:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-220</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>شبکه‌های تلویزیونی فارسی در خارج از کشور</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@usa_fa Farhad Allayari]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>روزهای مختلفی پیش میان که خیلی از مهاجران ایرانی در خارج از کشور به دنبال راهی برای تماشای تلویزیون های ایرانی خواهند بود. مثلا لحظه سال تحویل، بازی پرسپولیس و استقلال، یه بازی مهم ملی برای والیبال، المپیک، کشتی قهرمانی جهان، مناظره های تلویزیونی ریاست جمهوری و … . توی این پست توضیح میدیم که برای حل کردن این مشکلات چه راه حل هایی وجود دارند و مزایا و معایب هر کدوم چی هستند.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>وبسایت رسمی صدا و سیما</strong> به آدرس irib.ir. خیلی کند و خیلی ضعیف، شاید به این دلیل که سرورهای خارج از کشور زیادی ندارن. ولی برای پخش مستقیم رادیو معمولا مشکلی ندارن. مزیت مهمش شاید میتونه این باشه که به شبکه ها استانی و محلی هم دسترسی خواهید داشت.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>تلوبیون: <a href="http://telewebion.com" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">telewebion.com</a>.</strong> علاوه بر وبسایت، اپ برای موبایل و تلوزیون های هوشمند هم ارائه میدن. به آرشیو صدا و سیما دسترسی دارند و سریال ها و فیلم های سینمایی زیادی رو هم نشون میدن. هنگام پخش فوتبال های اروپا و یا هر گونه مسابقه ورزشی ای که صدا و سیما بدون مجوز پخش میکنه، دسترسی رو قطع می‌کنند و قوانین رو رعایت می‌کنند.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/original/1X/225d7f88deb3836b37083002fd6291413b157641.jpeg" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/4U0yhrWlVgUirXSbhwQzMEhFEm5.jpeg?dl=1" title="telew" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/225d7f88deb3836b37083002fd6291413b157641_2_690x243.jpeg" alt="telew" data-base62-sha1="4U0yhrWlVgUirXSbhwQzMEhFEm5" width="690" height="243" srcset="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/225d7f88deb3836b37083002fd6291413b157641_2_690x243.jpeg, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/225d7f88deb3836b37083002fd6291413b157641_2_1035x364.jpeg 1.5x, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/225d7f88deb3836b37083002fd6291413b157641_2_1380x486.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/225d7f88deb3836b37083002fd6291413b157641_2_10x10.png"></a></div><p></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>اپلیکشین Persian TV</strong>  این اپ برای گوشی‌های آیفون و اندروید وجود داره و شبکه های صدا و سیما رو پخش میکنه.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>سرویس Jadoo TV</strong> یک شرکت خصوصی ثبت شده در آمریکا که چهار package برای پخش زنده زبان های مختلف داره. در ازای هزینه اشتراک ماهانه میشه به شبکه های مختلف فارسی زبان های سراسر دنیا علاوه بر صدا و سیما دسترسی پیدا کرد. علاوه بر وبسایت، اپ های مختلف موبایل و تلویزیون ارائه میدن و حتی یک دستگاه پخش کننده مجزا هم دارند که میشه تهیه کرد.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/original/1X/8c1d211df5c0a159cae59d49b2f72479d454e6ea.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/jZvfP7UNN3fwCIMlqPSITnAXWUG.png?dl=1" title="jadoo" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/8c1d211df5c0a159cae59d49b2f72479d454e6ea_2_690x230.png" alt="jadoo" data-base62-sha1="jZvfP7UNN3fwCIMlqPSITnAXWUG" width="690" height="230" srcset="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/8c1d211df5c0a159cae59d49b2f72479d454e6ea_2_690x230.png, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/8c1d211df5c0a159cae59d49b2f72479d454e6ea_2_1035x345.png 1.5x, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/8c1d211df5c0a159cae59d49b2f72479d454e6ea_2_1380x460.png 2x" data-small-upload="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/8c1d211df5c0a159cae59d49b2f72479d454e6ea_2_10x10.png"></a></div><p></p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>وبسایت GLWiz</strong> یک سرویس دیگه که خیلی مشابه به Jadoo TV هست. تمام سرویس های Jadoo TV رو ارائه میدن و مثل Jadoo TV یه دستگاه پخش هم دارند که بهش میگن GL Box. یک بسته شبکه های ترک زبان هم دارند.</li>
</ul>
<p></p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/original/1X/7bf1b2ff06bca281b4194a80719281e41be5a546.jpeg" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/hGsz9D3GFjFAjx04IRf2t7DVOPs.jpeg?dl=1" title="glwiz" rel="noopener nofollow ugc"><img src="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/7bf1b2ff06bca281b4194a80719281e41be5a546_2_690x249.jpeg" alt="glwiz" data-base62-sha1="hGsz9D3GFjFAjx04IRf2t7DVOPs" width="690" height="249" srcset="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/7bf1b2ff06bca281b4194a80719281e41be5a546_2_690x249.jpeg, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/7bf1b2ff06bca281b4194a80719281e41be5a546_2_1035x373.jpeg 1.5x, https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/7bf1b2ff06bca281b4194a80719281e41be5a546_2_1380x498.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="https://global.discourse-cdn.com/standard10/uploads/sabjin/optimized/1X/7bf1b2ff06bca281b4194a80719281e41be5a546_2_10x10.png"></a></div><p></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>تماشالند</strong> به آدرس <a href="http://tamashaland.com" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">tamashaland.com</a>. توضیح دقیقی از اینکه این وبسایت متعلق به کجاست پیدا نکردیم ولی شبکه های صدا و سیما رو به صورت زنده پخش میکنه. بازی های جام باشگاه های اروپا و والیبال ها رو هم پخش میکنه که میتونه نشون دهنده این باشه که برای پخش، مجوزهای مربوطه برای خرید license و copy-right رو ندارند.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>فوتبالیترین</strong> <a href="http://footballitarin.com" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">footballitarin.com</a>. تمرکز این وبسایت فقط پخش زنده فوتباله. به طور خاص بازی‌های لیگ برتر ایران رو میتونید به صورت زنده از طریق لینک های مختلفی که وبسایت اراِئه میده نگاه کنید.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>شما چه وبسایت یا سرویس دیگه‌ای رو میشناسید که از قلم افتاده و باید به لیست اضافه بشه؟</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/topic/101#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 19:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-219</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Flying to USA from Canada</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@zia Zia]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I have had flights from Canada to the US several times and never had a bad experience. But it might also depend on your citizenship/residency status.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/flying-to-usa-from-canada/96#post_2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 14:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-218</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Starting bakery at home</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rozita Rozita Allahmanesh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Hello friends,</p>
<p>My mother and I are planning on starting a home bakery business. We are thinking about baking birthday cakes and Persian sweets. I have seen other folks doing the same thing in other cities both in USA and Canada but is this legal? Do we need to have some sort of license or permission? If yes, does anyone know what the process is to obtain such licenses?</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/starting-bakery-at-home/99#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 16:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-216</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Apartment Rent Increase</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@winner Hannah Anvari]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I don’t think you can fight back. The landlord can adjust the rent per market if your contract is over.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/apartment-rent-increase/98#post_2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 02:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-215</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Gardening Service</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@saba Saba Jamalian]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Another good idea is to ask your neighbors. Gardeners who are already working in the same area can afford offering discounts. Also, your neighbors probably have the same type of landscapes with similar issues.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/gardening-service/72#post_5</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 02:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-214</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Career Advice Needed</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@rozita Rozita Allahmanesh]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I 100% agree with what <a class="mention" href="https://sabjin.com/u/mary">@mary</a> said. I also want to add that there are companies that rent out rooms to stylists. One example I know is Sola Salon: <a href="https://www.solasalonstudios.com/" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">https://www.solasalonstudios.com/</a><br>
They rent out private rooms to hair stylists where you can advertise to your customers.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/career-advice-needed/97#post_3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 18:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-213</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Apartment Rent Increase</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@deli Delaram Soofi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>My landlord increased my rent by 16% after just one year. Is this legal? How can I fight back?</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/apartment-rent-increase/98#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 17:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-212</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Career Advice Needed</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@mary Maryam Dashti]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Have you looked into starting your own business? Beauty Salons rent out their chairs by the hour. I would call all the nearby salons to ask for a chair, and then you can start building your own clientele. It sounds more difficult than it is. It will be tough in the first few months but rewarding in the long run.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/career-advice-needed/97#post_2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 16:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-211</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Career Advice Needed</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@winner Hannah Anvari]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I worked as a hair designer in a beauty salon in Iran for seven years before coming to America. The only related job I could ever find was at a Supre Cut location with almost minimum wage. How can I get my career started in a beauty salon? Nowhere I go has current openings…</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/career-advice-needed/97#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 21:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-210</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Flying to USA from Canada</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@farhad Farhad Tasnimpour]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I’ll be flying from Toronto to San Francisco in a couple of weeks. Anything I should be aware of or concerned about as an Iranian? I have heard not great things about treatments at the border…</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/flying-to-usa-from-canada/96#post_1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 20:13:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-209</guid>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
