<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Security Card and SSN in USA</title>
    <link>https://sabjin.com/t/social-security-card-and-ssn-in-usa/112</link>
    <description>**All You Need to Know About the Social Security Number and Social Security Card in The United States.**

For a new immigrant, it is not unlikely that you must have heard the term Social Security Number or SSN, as it is mainly called. Are you wondering what it is and if you should get one? In this post, we go over the basics of an SSN and every other thing you need to know about an SSN as an immigrant. 

What is a Social Security Number? 
- A Social Security number (SSN) is a numerical identifier assigned to U.S. citizens and other residents. The origin of the social security number dates back to 1936. The integration into the security system was basically to provide retirement and disability benefits for U.S. citizens. But as you would see in the rest of this post, it has grown to be more than that.

What does a Social Security Number Entail? 
- You must understand that while a social security number might contain a series of random numbers, the numbers are far from random. There is a set metric for how they are given. Each SSN is a compilation of three groups of numbers. This is the area number, group number, and serial number. 
The first three numbers on an SSN are the area number, and every area has a definitive structure of numbers assigned to the area. At the same time, the group number refers to the SSN issuing office, which ranges from 01-99. The serial number, on the other hand, is made in such a way that it ascends from 0001 to 9999 within each group. 0000 is never given, and no two persons have the same four serial number digits. 

Why do I need a Social Security Number?
- Coming into the United States, you want to make sure that you get every benefit that applies to you. More so, during applications for job offers, passport applications, loans request, tax payments, and driver&#39;s license applications, it is required that you input your social security number. This number makes it possible to track and apply for benefits. 
Getting an SSN and the SSN card showing the number as an immigrant requires you to fill out Form SS-5: Application for a Social Security Card from the SSA. While going through the form, you would see how to obtain an original card, replace a card, and change or correct SSN records. However, obtaining these cards and numbers comes with a couple of requirements, such as documentation that proves age, identity, and immigration status. All at zero cost. 

What should you do if your Social Security Number Card is Stolen?  
- It is pretty common these days to hear of identity thieves. But once you suspect that your identity has been stolen and your social security number has been used by someone else, you are required to act immediately. 
Contact the Social Security Administration if you suspect income-related problems after reporting the suspected criminal activity to your financial institutions and credit reporting agencies. You can also file complaints with IdentityTheft.gov, the Internal Revenue Service, and the Internet Crime Center to report any suspicious activity.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 21:05:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Uncategorized</category>
    <atom:link href="https://sabjin.com/t/social-security-card-and-ssn-in-usa/112.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Social Security Card and SSN in USA</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Marzieh Akbarpour]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><strong>All You Need to Know About the Social Security Number and Social Security Card in The United States.</strong></p>
<p>For a new immigrant, it is not unlikely that you must have heard the term Social Security Number or SSN, as it is mainly called. Are you wondering what it is and if you should get one? In this post, we go over the basics of an SSN and every other thing you need to know about an SSN as an immigrant.</p>
<p>What is a Social Security Number?</p>
<ul>
<li>A Social Security number (SSN) is a numerical identifier assigned to U.S. citizens and other residents. The origin of the social security number dates back to 1936. The integration into the security system was basically to provide retirement and disability benefits for U.S. citizens. But as you would see in the rest of this post, it has grown to be more than that.</li>
</ul>
<p>What does a Social Security Number Entail?</p>
<ul>
<li>You must understand that while a social security number might contain a series of random numbers, the numbers are far from random. There is a set metric for how they are given. Each SSN is a compilation of three groups of numbers. This is the area number, group number, and serial number.<br>
The first three numbers on an SSN are the area number, and every area has a definitive structure of numbers assigned to the area. At the same time, the group number refers to the SSN issuing office, which ranges from 01-99. The serial number, on the other hand, is made in such a way that it ascends from 0001 to 9999 within each group. 0000 is never given, and no two persons have the same four serial number digits.</li>
</ul>
<p>Why do I need a Social Security Number?</p>
<ul>
<li>Coming into the United States, you want to make sure that you get every benefit that applies to you. More so, during applications for job offers, passport applications, loans request, tax payments, and driver’s license applications, it is required that you input your social security number. This number makes it possible to track and apply for benefits.<br>
Getting an SSN and the SSN card showing the number as an immigrant requires you to fill out Form SS-5: Application for a Social Security Card from the SSA. While going through the form, you would see how to obtain an original card, replace a card, and change or correct SSN records. However, obtaining these cards and numbers comes with a couple of requirements, such as documentation that proves age, identity, and immigration status. All at zero cost.</li>
</ul>
<p>What should you do if your Social Security Number Card is Stolen?</p>
<ul>
<li>It is pretty common these days to hear of identity thieves. But once you suspect that your identity has been stolen and your social security number has been used by someone else, you are required to act immediately.<br>
Contact the Social Security Administration if you suspect income-related problems after reporting the suspected criminal activity to your financial institutions and credit reporting agencies. You can also file complaints with <a href="http://IdentityTheft.gov" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">IdentityTheft.gov</a>, the Internal Revenue Service, and the Internet Crime Center to report any suspicious activity.</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="https://sabjin.com/t/social-security-card-and-ssn-in-usa/112/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://sabjin.com/t/social-security-card-and-ssn-in-usa/112/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 21:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">sabjin.com-post-112-1</guid>
        <source url="https://sabjin.com/t/social-security-card-and-ssn-in-usa/112.rss">Social Security Card and SSN in USA</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
